Cole, David L. Papers 5588
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- National Conference of Christians and Jews, Inc., 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Correspondence with various officers of the organization re organizing chapter in Passaic County with Cole's assistance; fund raising, membership, etc.
- N, 1944-1960 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
  With National Industrial Conference Board re attending discussion meetings, etc.; National War Labor Board, routine; New Jersey Board of Mediation re mediation cases; New York School of Social Work re Cole teaching a course and routine; New York State Board of Mediation re labor mediator applicants and the interview method (with George Taylor and others); Richard M. Nixon thanking Cole for his work during the longshore negotiations; other routine and personal.
- O, 1944-1954 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  Frank O'Connell, Assistant Secretary of Defense re routine and personal; other routine and personal.
- P, 1944-1955 (Box 5, Folder 7-10)
  With Selig Perlman, University of Wisconsin re literary, collective bargaining theories, Railway Labor Act, personal and routine; other routine and personal.
- Q, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Routine.
- R (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
  With Victor Riesel, Post-Hall Syndicate, Inc. re articles on New York City Transit dispute, diesel dispute, and routine; with Nelson Rockefeller re Rockefeller Commission thanking Cole for his work on the Governor's Special Committee to study the employer and employee relations in public service and letter thanking Cole for his support during Rockefeller's presidential nomination campaign.
- S, 1952-1954 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  Secretary to Mr. Cole - correspondence while he was out of town concerning official business matters.
- S, 1944-1956 (Box 6, Folder 4-13)
  With Ralph T. Seward, arbitrator and personal friend; Sumner H. Slichter, Harvard University; Lewis L. Strauss, (Chairman, Atomic Energy Commission) re personal; other routine and personal.
- T, 1945-1954 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  With George W. Taylor, Chairman, National War Labor Board re various cases and personal and other subjects of mutual interest; Textile Workers of America with various correspondents re grievances; Harry S Truman - letters appointing Cole as member of Steel Industry Board (1949) and Cole asking Truman for a photograph; other routine and personal.
- U-V, 1944-1955 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Routine and personal.
- W, 1944-1955 (Box 7, Folder 5-9)
  W. Willard Wirtz, Professor, Northwestern University (Secretary, Department of Labor) re report on union shop issue, thanking Cole for serving on Missile Sites Commission and miscellaneous; Sidney A. Wolff re various cases and congratulating Cole on being selected as permanent umpire for International Harvester and other routine and personal.
- X-Z, 1943-1955 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Atomic Energy Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Relations in Atomic Energy., 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Committee's Report.
- Atomic Energy Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Relations in Atomic Energy., 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
  Committee's Report and correspondence.
- Atomic Energy Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Relations in Atomic Energy., 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 4-7)
  Articles pertinent to Atomic Energy.
- Atomic Energy Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Relations in Atomic Energy., 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 8-11)
  Expenses.
- Atomic Energy Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Relations in Atomic Energy. (Box 9, Folder 1-6)
  Committee Reports.
- Atomic Energy Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Relations in Atomic Energy., 1954-1957 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  Cole's notes.
- Atomic Energy Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Relations in Atomic Energy., 1954-1957 (Box 9, Folder 9-11)
  Sprague, Nickerson Reports; letters from J. Keith Mann and J. A. Brownlow.
- Atomic Energy Commission. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Correspondence.
- Atomic Energy Commission. (Box 10, Folder 2-4)
  Miscellaneous.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  Case notes.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 6-9)
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Stenographer's minutes before FMCS Board of Inquiry, 6/21/48.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948 (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
  Stenographer's minutes before FMCS Board of Inquiry, 6/22/48.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  Stenographer's minutes before FMCS Board of Inquiry, 6/23/48.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  Stenographer's minutes before FMCS Board of Inquiry, 6/24/48.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  Coal Board of Inquiry, cont.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948-1950 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  "Principal Documents in 1948 Bituminous Coal Wage Negotiations."
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948-1950 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Statements for injunctions.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948-1950 (Box 11, Folder 5-8)
  Statements of witnesses before Board.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1950 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Agreement of 1950 - communications from John L. Lewis to UMW membership.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1948-1950 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  Miscellaneous - includes newspaper clippings, travel vouchers, etc.
- Coal Board of Inquiry., 1967 (Box 11, Folder 11-14)
  Notes from meetings - transcripts.
- Council of Economic Advisors., 1968 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Economic Report of the President, February 1968, together with Annual Report of the Council of Economic Advisers.
- Council of Economic Advisors. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  Miscellaneous, including travel vouchers and correspondence with Arthur Okun (Chairman of Council of Economic Advisors) regarding Task Force on Wage-Price Policy.
- Council of Economic Advisors. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Recommendations of Task Force on Wage-Price Policy, Interim Report of Task Force, Memorandum to President from Chairman of Council of Economic Advisors Okun and Weekly Compilation of Presidential Documents.
- Council of Economic Advisors., 1969 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Consultant - FMCS. Includes correspondence with J. Curtis Counts, Director of Services.
- Council of Economic Advisors. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  Travel vouchers, etc.
- Council of Economic Advisors., 1962 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Information on Canadian Maritime Union - Seafarers International Union dispute; correspondence, Board of Inquiry Reports, factual background on dispute.
- Council of Economic Advisors., 1962 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Council of Economic Advisors. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  "Statement of Seafarers International Union of North America, AFL-CIO, In the Matter of the Dispute with Upper Lakes Shipping Company and its Subsidiaries," includes exhibits for the case.
- Council of Economic Advisors., 1951 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Economic Cooperation Administration Includes correspondence with John Nickerson, Chairman, and announcement of the creation of this administration.
- Council of Economic Advisors., 1951 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Economic Stabilization Agency. Includes correspondence with Allan Valentine, Administrator; travel vouchers, etc.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  Correspondence with Frederick Livingston concerning creation of Public Employee Relations Board; with George W. Tayler, Chairman of the Committee, re bill to replace Cordin-Wadlin Act.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  Memoranda to members of the Committee from E. Wight Bakke, New York Chamber of Commerce, and George Taylor, concerning public employee relations, means to avoid strikes in public sector, etc.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1957 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Old Documents for Committee Use Includes statements concerning 1957 amendment to NLRA with respect to conciliation of labor disputes.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 13, Folder 8-10)
  Staff Study Papers 1-13 on various aspects of New York State Public Employee Relations: history, legislation, enforcement, etc.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  Travel vouchers.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1966 (Box 13, Folder 121-4)
  Drafts of Committee reports, and public hearings of the Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1966 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Interim Reports of Committee, March 31, 1966.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Final Reports.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  D. L. Cole's notes on Committee work.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Proposed amendments to Cordin-Wadlin Act and copies of the Taylor Act.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  Miscellaneous Includes newspaper and magazine articles, American Bar Association and other relevant materials.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  Miscellaneous Bibliography of Public Sector Relations, related articles.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  "Deterrents and Penalties" - statement of the Committee concerning no-strike principle in public sector.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 14, Folder 8-10)
  New York Civil Service Employees Association Legislative information, ballots, constitution and by-laws, chapter officers' manual, membership reports, etc.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Legal opinions concerning constitutionality of the no-strike clause of the Taylor law.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  Statement of procedures under the Taylor law, guidelines for local public employers' and employees' organizations on Taylor law, press releases concerning Taylor law decisions.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  Reports on the beginning months of the Taylor law..
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  New York City Procedures - Taylor Law. Correspondence with Office of Collective Bargaining.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1965 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  Public Employee Labor Relations - Selected Materials - Cordin-Wadlin Law, Rosetti Bill. 1965, etc.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1965 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  Related Documents.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  Releases of Public Employment Relations Board.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  "The Taylor Law and the Strike Ban" by Donald Wollett, "Teacher Negotiations and School Decentralization" by Michael Moskow and Kenneth McLennan.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  Issues of PERB News, and releases of the New York Chamber of Commerce regarding the Taylor law.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1968 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  David L. Cole's notes on the Governor's Conference on Public Employee Relations, October 14-16, 1968.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 16, Folder 2-5)
  Governor's Conference on Public Employment Relations Remarks, correspondence, etc.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  Memoranda to members of the Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations from Richard Willfield. 12/68-1/69.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1968 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  Interim Committee Reports. May 1968.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1968 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  Interim Committee Reports. June 1968.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1967 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  Miscellaneous file used by Cole Includes report by Ted Kheel on A. J. Travia's report on Taylor law; PERB articles; newspaper articles; "Arbitration and Federal Rights under Collective Agreements in 1967" by Edgar Sores and Peter Anderson.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  Miscellaneous file used by Cole Includes PERB's report on first 6 months of Taylor Law by Robert Hebsby and Cole's notes on this report. Also statement of Office of Collective Bargaining on Public Employee Relations.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  Miscellaneous Includes Cole's comments on Kheel's report (ff 9); pamphlet "Good Government" by George Taylor, Jerry Wurf, and Jerome Lefkowitz.
- Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations., 1968 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  Recalling of Taylor Committee by Governor Rockefeller; correspondence re the Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations, 1968.
- Governor Robert B. Meyner's Committee on Public Utility Labor Disputes Legislation., 1954 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  Committee's Report to the Governor, 9/54, includes letter to the Governor from the Committee.
- Governor Robert B. Meyner's Committee on Public Utility Labor Disputes Legislation. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Committee's Report to the Governor, with corrections and notes
- Governor Robert B. Meyner's Committee on Public Utility Labor Disputes Legislation. (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
  Drafts of Part I of the Report: "The Problem: Summary of Government Experiences, Analysis, and Conclusions," includes notes and corrections
- Governor Robert B. Meyner's Committee on Public Utility Labor Disputes Legislation. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  Drafts of Part V of the Report: "The Committee's Findings and Recommendations," includes notes and corrections.
- Governor Robert B. Meyner's Committee on Public Utility Labor Disputes Legislation. (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
  Cole's copies of Committee's report, includes his notes, and correspondence with other committee members concerning the drafts
- Governor Robert B. Meyner's Committee on Public Utility Labor Disputes Legislation. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  Committee Secretary Allan Weisenfeld's notes on Committee meetings
- Governor Robert B. Meyner's Committee on Public Utility Labor Disputes Legislation. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  David Cole's notes on Committee work.
- Governor Robert B. Meyner's Committee on Public Utility Labor Disputes Legislation. (Box 17, Folder 10-12)
  Correspondence. Includes correspondence with Committee members Carl Fulda, Richard Lester, Art Carpenter, Allan Weisenfeld and respondents to a questionnaire prepared by the committee
- Governor Robert B. Meyner's Committee on Public Utility Labor Disputes Legislation. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Miscellaneous related publications. Includes copies of related congressional acts. "State Powers in Labor Relations" by Helen Shaffer; analysis of New Jersey Statute Concerning Labor Disputes by Sol Kapelsohn; Congressional records; "Strike Controls in Essential Industries" by Herbert Northrup.
- Governor Robert B. Meyner's Committee on Public Utility Labor Disputes Legislation., 1954 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  Miscellaneous related publications. "Work Stoppages," U.S. Department of Labor, Monthly Report (4/54); "Monthly Report - Current Wage Developments"; American Bar Association papers; "Compulsory Arbitration of Utility Disputes in New Jersey and Pennsylvania" by Robert France, and Richard Lester.
- Department of Labor. Labor Management Relations Committee. (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
  Correspondence. Includes correspondence with Louis Hodges, Chairman.
- Department of Labor. Labor Management Relations Committee. (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
  Cole's notes on the Committee and Committee list.
- Department of Labor. Labor Management Relations Committee. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  Includes memoranda for Committee members and Committee reports.
- Department of Labor. Labor Management Relations Committee. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  Related publications. 12NOW, publication of American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE), Local 12; agreements between U.S. Department of Labor and AFGE; agreements between Labor-Management Services Administration and National Union of Compliance Officers
- Department of Labor. Labor Management Relations Committee. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  Report of Committee.
- Department of Labor. Labor Management Relations Committee. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  AFGE information.
- Department of Labor. Labor Management Relations Committee. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  Report to the President and comments on the report, etc.
- Department of Labor. Labor Management Relations Committee. (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
  Report of Panel for Improvement of Labor-Management Relations in the U.S. Department of Labor.
- Department of Labor. Labor Management Relations Committee., 1951 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  Senate Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations, 1951. Includes correspondence with Hubert Humphrey, newsletters, statement by Cole.
- Industrial Relations Committee for Johnson and Humphrey. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, etc.
- Maritime Industry Board of Inquiry., 1953-1968 (Box 19, Folder 2-3)
  Notes, reports, correspondence, etc. 1953, 1968.
- Maritime Industry Board of Inquiry. (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
  Statements of the President, unions, Marine Engineers Beneficial Association (MEBA), Pacific Maritime Association, etc.
- Maritime Industry Board of Inquiry., 1961 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  Records of First and Second Sessions of the Board of Inquiry, June 1961.
- Maritime Industry Board of Inquiry., 1961 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  Records of Third and Fourth Sessions of the Board of Inquiry, June 1961.
- Maritime Industry Board of Inquiry., 1961 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  David L. Cole's notes.
- Maritime Industry Board of Inquiry. (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
  Reports of the Board of Inquiry to the President.
- Maritime Industry Board of Inquiry. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  "Impact of Maritime Collective Bargaining on the Shipping Industry" and "The Big Issue is Jobs".
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  Synopsis of Board of Inquiry Activities, copies of an agreement between MEBA
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
  Correspondence re dispute settlement.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  Copies of settlement with Cole's notes.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
  Papers relating to the agreement, changes, proposals, etc.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  Miscellaneous. Includes synopsis of Presidential Boards of Inquiry created under National Emergency Provisions of the Labor Management Relations Act.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  Miscellaneous. Includes report to the President.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  Includes contract proposals, arbitration opinion between International Longshoremen's Association and New York Shipping Association, Inc
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  Missile Sites Labor Commission. Cole's notes on Commission activities.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  National Citizens' Commission on International Cooperation. Includes correspondence with Hubert H. Humphrey and Adlai Stevenson.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  Includes pamphlets on civil rights, bi-racial committees.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  Correspondence on urban problems, job opportunities, etc.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  Correspondence concerning report of the Commission. Includes list of names to which the report of NCIP was sent.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1975 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  List of Commission members; "Comments concerning draft statement of March 20, 1975 on FCMS Implementation of NCIP Recommendations, Report to Congress on FCMS Implementation of these Recommendations.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  Includes information relevant to NCIP, including news releases; press clippings; unused report to the President; executive order relative to NCIP; memorandum for the President.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  Includes information relevant to NCIP. Speeches: Ralph T. Seward to the National Academy of Arbitrators; "The Arbitration of Labor Disputes" by E. L. Oliver, "How to Stop Strikes by Really Trying" by Donald B. Straus, "Arbitration - Whose Responsibility" by David L. Cole.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  Cole's notes on NCIP.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  Reports, interim reports, drafts of reports of the NCIP.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  Reports, interim reports, drafts of reports of the NCIP
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 21, Folder 13)
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 21, Folder 14)
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  Correspondence regarding NCIP.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  Miscellaneous. Minutes of meetings of NCIP, etc.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  Speeches and paper related to NCIP. "Railroads and the Energy Crisis" by Al H. Chesser, President - United Transportation Union; "Exploring Alternatives to the Strike" by David L. Cole.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1973 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  Papers related to NCIP. "Freeze and Phase IV" and "Phase IV Announcement" of the Economic Stabilization Program, 1973.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  Papers related to NCIP. Includes newspaper clippings; information on the Toledo Labor-Management-Citizens Committee; Keynote Address by Robert E. Hampton at the Federal Bar Assoc. Nat'l. Conference on Labor Relations in the Federal Service.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1973 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  Papers relating to NCIP. "The Quality of Work Program of the National Commission on Productivity - a Statement of Intent," a memorandum for the Secretary of Commerce on the West Coast Longshore Contract Negotiations, 1973.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  Papers relating to NCIP - Newspaper clippings Notice of meeting - NCIP; items from current Developments section - Bureau of National Affairs (BNA).
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1972 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  Reference documents, speeches, etc. relating to NCIP. "Report of the Secretary of Labor's Advisory Committee on Labor Management Relations in Atomic Energy Installations"; "Hearings Before the Subcommittee on Labor of the Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, U.S. Senate, 1972"; "Role of National Commission for Industrial Peace" - David L. Cole.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1961 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  Reference documents relating to NCIP. "The Public Interest in National Labor Policy" by Committee for Economic Development. 1961
- National Commission for Industrial Peace. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  Reference Documents relating to NCIP. "Current Developments Section" from the BNA; "New Inroads in Achieving Industrial Peace" by Cole, "Collective Bargaining and Industrial Peace" by Cole.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  Reference documents relating to NCIP. "Calendar of Wage Increases and Negotiations for 1974" by John Garney; "Labor and the Economy in 1973" by Catherine C. Defina; "Developments in Industrial Relations"; "A Changing Labor Relations Setting"; "Collective Bargaining - A Report by the President's Advisory Committee on Labor-Management Policy.
- National Commission for Industrial Peace., 1972 (Box 22, Folder 12)